James A. Pike Papers
James A. Pike Papers
- Correspondence
  - [General], 1936; 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - [General], 1940 (Box 1)
  - [General], 1942-1951 (Box 1)
  - [General], 1952 Jan-1953 Feb (Box 2)
  - [General], 1953 Mar-Nov (Box 3)
  - [General], 1953 Nov-1954 Apr (Box 4)
  - [General], 1954 Apr-1955 Feb (Box 5)
  - [General], 1955 Mar-1956 Jan (Box 6)
  - [General], 1956 Feb-Aug (Box 7)
  - [General], 1956 Sep-1957 Jan (Box 8)
  - [General], 1957 Feb-May (Box 9)
  - [General], 1957 Jun-Oct (Box 10)
  - [General], 1957 Oct-1958 Feb (Box 11)
  - [General], 1958 Feb (Box 12)
  - [General], 1958 Feb-Apr (Box 13)
  - [General], 1958 May-1960 Mar (Box 14)
  - [General], 1960 Apr-1961 Aug (Box 15)
  - [General], 1961 Oct-1963 Mar (Box 16)
  - [General], 1963 Apr-1964 Oct (Box 17)
  - [General], 1964 Nov-1965 Aug (Box 18)
  - [General], 1965 Aug-1966 Feb (Box 19)
  - [General], 1966 Mar-May (Box 20)
  - [General], 1966 May-Aug (Box 21)
  - [General], 1966 Sep-Oct (Box 22)
  - [General], 1966 Oct (Box 23)
  - [General], 1966 Oct-Nov (Box 24)
  - [General], 1966 Nov (Box 25)
  - [General], 1966 Nov-Dec (Box 26)
  - [General], 1967 Jan (Box 27)
  - [General], 1967 Feb-Mar (Box 28)
  - [General], 1967 Mar-May (Box 29)
  - [General], 1967 May-Jul (Box 30)
  - [General], 1967 Jul-Aug (Box 31)
  - [General], 1967 Sep (Box 32)
  - [General], 1967 Oct (Box 33)
  - [General], 1967 Nov-Dec (Box 34)
  - [General], 1968 Jan-Feb (Box 35)
  - [General], 1968 Feb-Apr (Box 36)
  - [General], 1968 May-Aug (Box 37)
  - [General], 1968 Sep-Nov (Box 38)
  - [General], 1968 Nov-Dec (Box 39)
  - [General], 1969 Jan-Apr (Box 40)
  - [General], 1969 May-Dec (Box 41)
  - Restricted correspondence, 1953-1968 (Box 41)
    Restriction expired, 2000.
  - [General], 1969; 6 folders (Box 42)
  - [General], 1969; 5 folders (Box 43)
  - [General], 1969; 3 folders (Box 44)
  - Unsorted, most is from 1960s; 2 folders (Box 44)
  - Unsorted, most is from 1960s; 6 folders (Box 45)
  - Unsorted, most is from 1960s; 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Notebooks
    - "MASTER FILE", 1955-1956; 2 volumes (Box 46)
    - "MASTER FILE", 1957; 3 volumes (Box 47)
    - "MASTER FILE", 1958 Jan (Box 48)
    - "MASTER FILE", 1958 Feb (Box 48)
    - "CALIFORNIA", 1958 Feb (Box 48)
    - "MASTER FILE", 1958 Mar (Box 49)
    - "CALIFORNIA", 1958 Mar (Box 49)
    - "MASTER FILE", 1958 Apr (Box 49)
    - "CALIFORNIA", 1958 Apr (Box 50)
    - "MASTER FILE", 1958 May (Box 50)
    - "CALIFORNIA", 1958 May (Box 50)
    - "CONFIDENTIAL", 1958 Jan-May (Box 51)
- Financial and legal records
  - Agreements, books, 1964 (Box 51)
  - Application to New York State Bar (Box 51)
  - Application for total disability income provision, government life insurance, 1965 (Box 51)
  - Bank records (Box 51)
  - Bank statements
    - Bishop's Discretionary Account, 1960-1962 (Box 51)
    - Bishop's Special Account, 1959-1966 (Box 51)
  - Book lists, 2 folders (Box 51)
  - Book orders completed, 7 folders (Box 52)
  - Calif. Advisory Committee, U.S. Civil Rights Commission (Box 52)
  - Certificate of registration of claim of copyright for Sunday School Bulletin, St. John's Church, 1946 (Box 52)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons royalty reports (Box 52)
  - Checkbooks
    - Bishop's Discretionary Fund, 1959-1962; 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Bishop's Special Fund, 1961-1962 (Box 52)
    - Bishop's Special Fund, 1962-1966; 4 folders (Box 53)
  - Church taxation (Box 53)
  - Civil Rights Commission (Box 53)
  - Civil rights temporary (Box 53)
  - Computer Dating Service (Box 54)
  - Contracts, speaking engagements, 1959-1969 (Box 54)
  - Deposition in support of admission of Wm. Stringfellow to New York State Bar, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Divorce papers (Pike vs. Pike), 1940-1941 (Box 54)
  - Doubleday royalties (Box 54)
  - Harper and Row file (Box 54)
  - Harper and Row royalty reports, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Law course (Box 54)
  - Legal contracts (Box 54)
  - New York State Bar (Box 54)
  - Petition to Appellate Division of N.Y. Supreme Court for admission to New York State Bar, 1957 (Box 54)
  - Pike Foundation (Box 54)
  - Prentice Hall royalty reports (Box 54)
  - Promissory notes relating to Bishop's Discretionary Fund, 1959-1960 (Box 54)
  - Real estate tax matters (Box 54)
  - Research Aid Fund (Box 54)
  - The Seabury Press Royalty Reports (Box 54)
  - Statements of balance in Bishop's Discretionary Fund, 1959-1962 (Box 54)
  - Statements regarding automobile accident in Topeka, Kansas, 1954; typescript copy, 2 pp. (Box 54)
  - Trustee Account (Box 54)
- Memorabilia
  - Academic transcripts, 1934; 1943 (Box 55)
  - Article containing mention of Pike ancestor, Harper's Monthly, 1868; published material (Box 55)
  - Autographs from books given to Pike by authors, holograph (Box 55)
  - Awards, 1934-1967 (Box 56)
  - Awards, 1936-1963 (Oversize 1)
  - Awards, 1958; 1962; includes Louis Brandeis Award (Oversize 2)
  - Awards, 1956; Jewish War Veterans of the United States (Oversize 8)
  - Badges (Box 55)
  - Biographical material
    - [General], 1936-1949 (Box 55)
    - Vassar controversy, 1949-1950 (Box 55)
    - [General], 1950-1953; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Sewanee controversy, 1953 (Box 55)
    - [General], 1954-1955; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - [General], 1956 (Box 57)
    - Television show, 1955-1956 (Box 57)
    - "Baby Doll" controversy, 1956-1957 (Box 57)
    - [General], 1957 (Box 57)
    - Television show, 1957 (Box 57)
    - Zellerbach Commission, 1957 Oct (Box 57)
    - [General], 1958 (Box 57)
    - Election as Bishop, 1958 Feb (Box 57)
    - [General], 1959-1960; 6 folders (Box 58)
    - [General], 1960-1961 Mar; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Houston Lenten Services, 1961 Mar (Box 59)
    - [General], 1961 Apr-Jun, Sep-Dec; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - [General], 1962 Jan-1963 Jul; 6 folders (Box 60)
    - Glossolalia controversy, 1963 (Box 60)
    - [General], 1963 Aug-1965 Dec; 6 folders (Box 61)
    - [General], 1966-1967; 5 folders (Box 62)
    - General Convention, Seattle, 1967 Sep; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - [General], 1968-1969; 4 folders (Box 63)
    - Center Crisis, 1969 Jun (Box 63)
    - Death in Israel, 1969 Sep (Box 63)
    - [General], 1970 (Box 63)
    - Critical commentaries
      - [General], 1953-1965; 2 folders (Box 63)
      - [General], 1966-1969; 3 folders (Box 64)
      - Ball, Virginia, The Godless Christians, chap. VIII, 1966; typescript copy revised (Box 64)
      - Emberg, Duane H.; "Bishop Pike as Communicator", 1968 (Box 64)
      - Roush, Kenneth E., The New Agnostic, 1966?; typescript copy (Box 64)
    - Printed biographies, 1953-1966 (Box 64)
    - Scrapbooks
      - General Interest and Religion (Oversize 3)
      - Heresy and All That (Oversize 4)
      - Kim Meyer's and The Resignation (Oversize 5)
      - Political Opinion (Oversize 6)
      - [Untitled, red cover] (Oversize 6)
  - Brochure describing Cathedral of St. John the Divine, undated (Box 64)
  - Cambridge University coat of arms (Oversize 8)
  - Certificates naming Pike as Godfather, 1945; 1955 (Box 64)
  - Citations, 1942-1966 (Box 64)
  - Clippings (Box 64)
  - Clippings, 5 folders (Box 65)
  - Clippings, 5 folders (Box 70)
  - Clippings, 6 folders (Box 71)
  - Clippings, 2 folders (Box 72)
  - Coat of arms of Pike Family (Box 65)
  - Desk ornament, lion head with miter, below it the words "University of North Carolina, St. Paul's Chapel"; plaster and silver paint, with small wooden stand (Box 110)
  - Engagement calendar, General Theological Seminary and Union Theological Seminary, 1946-1947 (Box 66)
  - Introduction of Pike speech at Fordham University, 1967 (Box 66)
  - Invitations, 1944-1967 (Box 66)
  - Letters, framed, 1939-1942 (Oversize 7)
  - Letters, framed, 1939-1942 (Oversize 8)
  - Lists of names and addresses, 1964? (Box 66)
  - Music, dedicated to Pike: Norman Coke-Jephcott, "O Lord Support Us", 1953 (Box 66)
  - Nameplate used by Pike while with U.S. Maritime Commission, 1941? (Box 66)
  - Negative, Father Leon Harris letter of appreciation (Box 66)
  - Paintings, 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Photographs
    - Group photo, unidentified, bishops in front row seated, women in second row, men in suits in third row (Oversize 1)
    - Christ Church, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., 1947-1948
    - Columbia University, 1949-1950 (Box 67)
    - Lambeth Conference, 1958; includes separate list of everyone in photo
    - [General], 1952-1963?; 4 folders (Box 67)
    - [General], undated; includes General Albert Pike, Sovereign Grand Commander of Scottish Masons of the United States in Masonic regalia (Box 67)
  - Plaques, See Awards, above.
  - Postcards, blank (Box 67)
  - Programs, 1941-1956; 3 folders (Box 67)
  - Programs, 1957-1968; 5 folders (Box 68)
  - Programs, 1969; undated (Box 69)
  - Publicity materials, 1951-1968 (Box 69)
  - Random notes made by Pike in Israel, Sep 1969 (Box 69)
  - San Francisco magazine, Dec 1964; contains feature on Grace Cathedral (Box 69)
  - Sketches, includes caricature of Pike; 2 items (Box 69)
  - Testimonial statements regarding Bishop Pike, 1952-1966 (Box 69)
  - Unidentified dictaphone tape, undated (Box 69)
  - Wallet (Box 69)
  - Watercolor sketch of consecration as Bishop by Luther B. McKee, 1959 (Box 69)
  - Miscellaneous, includes two caricatures of Pike and the official notice prohibiting him from entering Rhodesia (Oversize 1)
- Personal records
  - Affiliations declined (Box 69)
  - Banks, 2 folders (Box 69)
  - Biography, 1969 (Box 69)
  - Birth certificate (Box 69)
  - Brunton Poetry (Box 69)
  - Charles Carroll (Box 69)
  - Correspondence (Box 73)
  - Engagements, 1966; 4 folders (Box 73)
  - Financial records, personal, 2 folders (Box 73)
  - Financial records, personal, 4 folders (Box 74)
  - Internal Revenue Service (IRS) (Box 74)
  - Income tax, 3 folders (Box 74)
  - Income tax, 2 folders (Box 75)
  - Insurance (Box 75)
  - Inventory of files from Center (Box 75)
  - Invitations declined, 1966 (Box 75)
  - Lawsuit, Avis (Box 75)
  - Legal (Box 75)
  - London trip (Box 75)
  - Medical (Box 75)
  - Medical information (Box 75)
  - Medical insurance (Box 75)
  - Margolis and Meternan (Box 75)
  - Marriage agreement (Box 75)
  - Memorial, Pike Forest (Box 75)
  - Passport (Box 75)
  - Pike family (Box 75)
  - Pike personal papers, 4 folders (Box 76)
  - Pike Jr. personal papers (Box 76)
- Professional records
  - as Lawyer, 1936-1944
    - Applications, 1943 (Box 76)
    - Bulletin of the Catholic University School of Law, 1939 (Box 76)
    - Naval orders, 1943 (Box 76)
    - Outline of discussion for Symposium on recent constructions of the federal rules, Sep 1940 (Box 76)
    - Securities and Exchange Comm. vs. Timetrust Inc., Summary of Complaint and answers (Box 76)
    - Statement of requirements for ordination, and list of books studied prior to ordination, 1943 (Box 76)
  - as Curate, St. John's, Washington, D.C., 1944-1946
    - Sunday School Bulletin of St. John's Church, 1945 Oct-1946 Apr; 2 folders (Box 76)
    - Sunday School Bulletin of St. John's Church, 1945 May-Nov; 3 folders (Box 77)
  - as Rector, Christ Church, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., 1947-1949
    - Canterbury Collegian, vol. 1, 1947 (Box 77)
    - Christ Church Courier, 1947-1949; volumes 1-3 (Box 77)
    - Contractual relations between vestry and rector; minutes of church meeting, 1935; 1949 (Box 77)
    - Sunday School Bulletin, 1947-1948 (Box 77)
    - Vassar controversy
      - Drafts of reports on the controversy, 1949 (Box 77)
      - Living Church article and replies, 1950 (Box 77)
      - Position statements, 1949? (Box 77)
  - as Chaplain, Columbia University, 1949-1952
    - Bulletins listing course offerings in religion, 1950-1953 (Box 77)
    - Certificate of election as Dean, Feb 1, 1952 (Box 77)
    - Chapel Bulletin, "Registration figures for religion courses 1949-1951", 1952 (Box 77)
    - Heuss Committee memoranda on meetings, 1950 Feb-Mar (Box 77)
    - Prospectus for Religious Studies at Columbia, 1949? (Box 77)
    - Report of the Chaplain, 1950 (Box 77)
  - as Dean, Cathedral of St. John the Divine, 1952-1958
    - Appointment as adjunct professor, 1953; 1955 (Box 77)
    - Bulletin of course offerings and registration figures for religion courses, 1957 (Box 77)
    - Committee on Annotation of Constitution and Canons
      - Draft publishing agreement with Seabury Press, 1953 (Box 77)
      - Forward to published edition [?], 1954 (Box 77)
      - Suggested changes in galley proof, 1953 (Box 77)
    - Course outlines and term paper suggestions for seminar on church and state, 1952-1958 (Box 77)
    - Customary of the Cathedral (Box 77)
    - Election as Bishop
      - Certificates of consent by Standing Committees, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Confidential reports on candidates, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Copies of documents relating to election, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Fact sheet on Pike and answers to questions about his intent, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Installation sermon by John Coburn, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Invitation lists, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Lists of people to contact in California, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Minutes of Standing Committee of Diocese of N.Y. and of Trustees of Cathedral, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Nominating speech, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Preparations for consecration, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Refusals of consent to election by Standing Committee, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Report of Nominating Committee, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Statements and correspondence re issue of divorce, 1958 (Box 77)
      - Tally sheets of votes for election and consent, 1958 (Box 78)
      - Testimonials of Electors, 1958 (Box 78)
      - Testimonial of election, 1958 (Box 78)
    - Itinerary of trip to Israel, 1956 (Box 78)
    - Joint Comm. on Structure and Organization of General Convention, Report and Recommendations, 1957 (Box 78)
    - Questionnaire of sub-committee on Constitutional rights, 1955 (Box 78)
    - Report to trustees of Cathedral, Oct 22 1957 (Box 78)
    - St. James, Wellfleet, Mass.
      - Architect's drawings, 1953 (Box 78)
      - Architect's plans, 1955 (Box 78)
      - By-laws of church, 1956 (Box 78)
      - Customary for the Chapel, 1957? (Box 78)
      - Materials relating to fund raising, 1955-1957 (Box 78)
      - Materials for descriptive brochures and order of worship, circa 1957 (Box 78)
      - Order of worship for dedication of chapel, Sep 1957 (Box 78)
      - Orders of Worship, 1957-1961 (Box 78)
      - Parochial reports, 1955-1957 (Box 78)
      - Photographs of model of church (Box 78)
      - Photographs of church and of church service (Box 78)
    - Schedules for TV show, 1955-1957 (Box 78)
    - Schedule for trip to Israel (Box 78)
    - Sewanee Controversy
      - Confidential report by members of protesting faculty, 1953; preliminary and final copies; 2 folders (Box 78)
      - Letter of Sewanee faculty requesting reconsideration of decision, 1953 (Box 78)
      - Materials relating to the Sewanee Witness Fund, 1953 (Box 78)
      - Paper by unknown author in support of admission of Negroes to Sewanee, 1953 (Box 78)
      - Report on issues involved in Sewanee controversy, Dept. of Christian Social Relations, 1953 (Box 78)
      - Statements by Pike re: refusal of degree, 1953 (Box 78)
    - South Africa Defense Fund, press release and list sponsors (Box 78)
    - Zellerbach Commission
      - Biographies of participants, 1957 (Box 79)
      - Information on particular refugee cases, 1957 (Box 79)
      - Itineraries and miscellaneous releases, 1957 (Box 79)
      - Preliminary report, 1957 (Box 79)
      - Report, 1957-1958 (Box 79)
      - Report, 1959 (Box 79)
      - U.N. Statutes on Refugees, resolution on refugees, undated (Box 79)
  - as Fifth Bishop of California, 1958-1966
    - Book list for summer course at Pacific School of Religion, 1965? (Box 79)
    - Bulletin of Church Divinity School of the Pacific, 1964 (Box 79)
    - California Advisory Committee to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Annual report, 1961 (Box 79, Box 49)
    - Canon IX of the missions of the diocese (Box 79)
    - Committee on Canon 36
      - Critical commentary on Dykman exposition by Pike, Nov 1962 (Box 79)
      - Draft statement by Pike, Aug 1962 (Box 79)
      - Exposition by Jackson Dykman, Jul 1962 (Box 79)
      - Revised draft of statement by Pike, Sep 1962 (Box 79)
      - Revised exposition by Dykman, Sep 1962 (Box 79)
    - Constitution and Canons of the Diocese of California, 1961 (Box 79)
    - Customary (revised), 1959? (Box 79)
    - Customary for bishop's use at marriage office with nuptial Eucharist, Nov 1962 (Box 79)
    - Draft letter cancelling speaking engagements for sabbatical, draft resolution naming Pike auxiliary bishop of diocese, 1965; 1966 (Box 79)
    - Heresy
      - Circular of Episcopalians for the Faith, 1961 (Box 79)
      - Materials re 1925 heresy trial of Bishop Brown, 1966? (Box 79)
      - Materials relating to church trials and civil review (Box 79)
      - Reply to charges filed by Bishop Harte, 1965 (Box 79)
    - House of Bishops, East Glacier, Montana
      - Journal of General Convention, Special Mtg., 1965 (Box 79)
      - Memo from Pike re Special Comm. on Deaconesses report, Sep 1965 (Box 79)
      - Miscellaneous material re Deaconess Phyllis Edwards, Apr 1965-Sep 1966 (Box 79)
      - Report of Special Committee on Deaconesses, Jun-Sep 1966 (Box 80)
    - House of Bishops, Wheeling, W. Va.
      - Journal of General Convention, Special Mtg., Oct 1966 (Box 80)
      - Letters replying to Louttit charges circulated to all Bishops, 1966 (Box 80)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1966 (Box 80)
      - Petition by Association of Episcopal Clergy, Oct 1966 (Box 80)
      - Press release by Pike charging Louttit with libel, Oct 11 1966 (Box 80)
      - Report of Dun Committee, resolution by Pike demanding trial, note on status of heresy court, 1966 (Box 80)
      - Resolution criticizing Bishops for denial of due process (American Council of Christian Churches), Oct 1966 (Box 80)
      - Statements on behalf of Pike by Southern California Rectors and by Bishop Cadigan, 1966 (Box 80)
      - Stringfellow, William and Towne, Anthony, The Bishop Pike Affair, 1967; galley page proofs annotated (Box 80)
      - Transcriptions of C B C tapes, Oct 1966 (Box 89)
    - Lambeth Conference arrangements, agenda, invitation, 1958 (Box 80)
    - Lecture notes from Cambridge, 1965 (Box 80)
    - Material relating to dismissal of undergraduate Chaplain at Berkeley, 1961 (Box 80)
    - Memoranda
      - Breach of confidential relationships, May 1965 (Box 80)
      - Canon 18: Interpretation, procedure, implementation, Apr 1964 (Box 80)
      - Canon 36: Constitutionality, 1962? (Box 80)
      - Canon 36: Ordination, sections 6a and 6b, 1962? (Box 80)
      - Canon 36: Ordination of George Hedley, 1960 (Box 80)
      - Canonical functions of Deacons, 1962; 1965 (Box 80)
      - Christian burial, undated (Box 80)
      - College work at Berkeley, 1959 (Box 80)
      - Communion: open and closed, 1959? (Box 80)
      - Confirmation visits, 1960 (Box 80)
      - Customaries
        - Burial Office and Requiem Eucharist, Jul 1965 (Box 80)
        - Dedication of a church, Oct 1964 (Box 80)
        - Eucharist and Confirmation, May 1965 (Box 80)
        - Institution of Ministers, Oct 1964 (Box 80)
        - Ordering of Priests, Oct 1964 (Box 80)
        - St. George's Chapel, El Rancho del Obispo, undated (Box 80)
        - Solemn Pontifical High Mass, Apr 1963 (Box 80)
      - Delegation of authority by Ordinary, Aug 1964 (Box 80)
      - Diocesan Customary, Feb 1965 (Box 80)
      - Examination in Greek, Aug 1965 (Box 80)
      - Freedom of prophecy and limitations, May 1965 (Box 80)
      - Lectors and lay readers, Nov 1964 (Box 80)
      - Ordering of Deaconess Phyllis Edwards, Apr 1965 (Box 80)
      - The Pax, Aug 1964? (Box 80)
      - Presbytery, Deanery, Diocesan structure, Mar 1962 (Box 80)
      - Presbytery structure, Sep 1962 (Box 80)
      - Press release about resignation, May 1966 (Box 80)
      - Press release about sabbatical, Jul 1965 (Box 80)
      - Proposed translation of the liturgy into modern English, Oct 1964 (Box 80)
      - Reorganization of diocesan staff and of the Council, Apr 1963 (Box 80)
      - Sabbatical leave, Jun 1965 (Box 80)
      - Telephone calls and appointments, Apr 1964 (Box 80)
      - Terms of reference for strategy committee, Jun 1965 (Box 80)
    - P et I Directives, 1959-1966 (Box 80)
    - Papers on Homosexuality, Bishop's Committee On Pastoral Counseling, 1962 (Box 81)
    - Pastoral letter, Charges of heresy, 1961 (Box 81)
    - Pastoral letter, Glossolalia, May 1963 (Box 81)
    - Pastoral letter, Racial discrimination and civil disobedience, Apr 1964 (Box 81)
    - Pastoral letter, to church at Harlingen, California, Jan 1965 (Box 81)
    - Position paper no. 10 of unknown strategy committee, Jun 1965 (Box 81)
    - Preliminary report of study commission on Glossolalia, 1963 (Box 81)
    - Press release on resignation as Bishop, memo on convention to elect new Bishop, 1966 (Box 81)
    - Press releases re banquet, last sermon, and election of new bishop, Aug-Sep 1966 (Box 81)
    - Proceedings of Bishop's Conference on Psychotherapy of Clergy, 1962 (Box 81)
    - Proposed program for Diocesan Stewardship, undated (Box 81)
    - Report of nominating committee re candidates for sixth bishop, Sep 1966 (Box 81)
    - Report of work at True Sunshine Mission, 1958 (Box 81)
    - Report on church buildings, May 1964 (Box 81)
    - Resolution in honor of Pike by trustees of Grace Cathedral, Jul 1966 (Box 81)
    - Resolution of sympathy by 116th Convention of Diocese of California, Feb 1966 (Box 81)
    - Schedule of confirmation visits, 1963 (Box 81)
    - Schedule of TV shows, 1958-1959 (Box 81)
    - Statutes of the Cathedral Church, Mar 1966 (Box 81)
  - Resignation as Bishop of California, 1966-1969
    - Bayne Commission
      - Final report, Aug 1967 (Box 81)
      - Preliminary statement, Advisory members, 1967 (Box 81)
      - Preliminary statement, Pike, 1967 (Box 81)
      - Quotation from Angus Dun speech to Church Congress, Apr 1924 (Box 81)
      - Statement by Presiding Bishop establishing committee and response by Pike, 1967 (Box 81)
      - Summary of final report (annotated), Sep 1967 (Box 81)
      - Transcript of interview on Today with Bishop Bayne, Sep 1967 (Box 81)
    - California Advisory Comm. to U.S. Civil Rights Commission
      - Introductory statement to hearings on Mexican-Americans, 1968 (Box 81)
      - Report on Mexican-Americans, 1968 (Box 81)
    - Center for Study of Democratic Institutions
      - Invitation to dinner in honor of Pike, 1966 (Box 81)
      - Materials re Pacem in Terris I, 1965 (Box 81)
      - Materials re Pacem in Terris II, 1967 (Box 81)
      - Misc. material re "Center Crisis", undated (Box 81)
      - Misc. memo re "Pike", 1967-1969 (Box 82)
      - Personnel memo, 1965-1966 (Box 82)
    - Draft proposal for purchase of The Churchman, 1968? (Box 82)
    - General Convention, Seattle, Washington
      - Agenda, press release, resolution, statements, Sep 1967 (Box 82)
      - Confidential memo, Stringfellow to Pike, Aug 1967 (Box 82)
      - Filmstrips, "Seattle Summary General Convention Color Filmstrip with Script 130 frames", 2 rolls film, plus narrator's and projectionist's scripts (Box 109)
      - Misc. notes, Sep 1967 (Box 82)
      - Resolutions re Bayne Report and heresy issue, 1967 (Box 82)
    - Misc. memoranda (Box 82)
    - Notes, Ripon College speaking engagement, 1967 (Box 82)
    - Organizational affiliation card file, 1969? (Box 82)
    - Open letter protesting Pike visit to Indio, California, Jan 1967 (Box 82)
    - Proposal for joint seminar on Law and Ethics in Church and State, Berkeley and G.T.U., 1966 (Box 82)
    - Sample itineraries, speaking engagements, 1967-1969 (Box 82)
    - Sample questions asked at lectures, 1967 (Box 82)